jonprell.com Cincinnati, OH www.github.com/JTP709

Full Stack Web Developer with four years of diverse professional experience in the field of Health and safety as an EHS Professional. Looking to leverage my drive for continuous improvement into a new career as a Full-Stack Engineer.

#### Education

Eastern Kentucky University - 4.0 GPA Richmond, KY Master of Science in Safety, Security, Emergency Management August 2015 Bachelor of Science in Homeland Security and Criminal Justice May 2012 www.udacity.com

Udacity Full Stack Nanodegree November 2017

## **Computer Skills**

- Programming, Database, and Markup Languages: Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks and Libraries: Flask, jQuery, Knockout.js, Bootstrap
- Additional Skills: Linux (Ubuntu distribution), AWS (Lightsail), Apache2 HTTP Server, Google Maps JavaScript API

#### **Projects**

## **Safety Management System**

Github Link

Compliance management system built on Python/Flask back-end with PostgreSQL database.

## **Emergency Event Manager**

#### Github Link

Real-time event mapping application built using Knockout's JavaScript library and framework and Google Maps API.

**Portfolio Site** Github Link

Professional portfolio site deployed on a Python/Flask back-end and jQuery front-end.

### Work Experience

Amazon.com Safety Specialist September 2015 – October 2017

Hebron, KY

- Collaborated with operations team to reduce night shift injuries by 50% through proactive engagement strategies, training, and concise reporting techniques.
- Deployed StrongArm Tech's FUSE Platform to achieve a 33% reduction in injuries in the most high-risk departments.
- Coordinated with Vaculux and Amazon Engineering to pilot a new material handling solution that generated a 10% increase in productivity with zero injuries on test stations.

# **Marathon Petroleum Company**

Health, Environmental, Safety and Security Co-Op

August 2014 – August 2015 Detroit, MI and Cincinnati, OH

- Authored emergency response plans and procedures, facilitated emergency management training, and coordinated with external emergency response agencies including the Cincinnati Fire and Police Departments.
- Collected noise dosimetry sampling data and produced a comprehensive noise isopleth for the MFD Refinery.

**Barnes Aerospace** 

September 2013 – May 2014

Environmental Health and Safety Co-Op

West Chester, OH

- Participated in Kaizen events that reduced employee exposure to air contaminants by 66% while reducing waste.
- Inventoried facility machinery and rebuilt the work order control system to reduce redundant work orders by 33%.

# **Kentucky Army National Guard**

Signals Intelligence Analyst

February 2006 – February 2008

Louisville, KY

Specialized in parsing metadata to create detailed analytical datasets for the 20th Special Forces Group (Airborne).